Let's add this backdrop and let's first of all create the backdrop component and add the styling for
Bu arka plan ekleyelim ve ncelikle arka plan bileeni oluturalm ve arka plan iin
the backdrop.
stil ekleyelim.
So let's head over to our UI folder in the backdrop
yleyse bizimle ba edelim Sen arka planda bir klasorsun.
and let's start working on that backdrop component,
Ve o zemin bileeni zerinde almaya balayalm.
it'll be a super simple component.
Sper basit bir bileen olacak.
As always it's a functional component here which receive some props and return some jsx,
Her zaman olduu gibi burada bir takmlar alan ve baz GSX iade eden ilevsel bir bileen.
it therefore also needs to import react from react and it needs to export itself as the default.
Bu nedenle de reak'i tepki olarak ie aktarmas gerekir ve kendisini varsaylan olarak da aktarmas gerekir.
Now in the jsx code I return,
imdi J'de X kodu dnyorum.
I don't actually even need to write complex code
Aslnda karmak kod yazmam bile gerekmiyor.
I just want to check if props.show is true,
Sadece pervane gsterisinin doru olup olmadn kontrol etmek istiyorum.
if that is the case, again using a ternary expression here, if that is the case then I want to return a div,
Durum byle bir durumda bir dn ifadesi kullanan durum yine de buysa, bu def'nin yalnzca ne
this div will simply hold the styling for the backdrop
arka plan durdurmak iin tutaca bir lm dndrmek istiyorum.
otherwise I will return null.
Aksi halde NULL dndrr.
You may return null in components, that is OK, it just means nothing gets rendered but it is OK,
imdi, tamam olan bileenlere dnebilir veya sadece hibir ey ilenemeyeceiniz anlamna gelir, ancak sorun yoktur.
now I don't need to pass any content to the div, I need to set up some styling though.
imdi div iin herhangi bir ierik aktarmaya ihtiyacm yok ama baz stil ayarlamam gerekiyor.
So let's add a backdrop.css file where we add some styling for the backdrop and
imdi arka plan iin baz stil eklediimiz C S S dosyasna bir zemin ekleyelim.
we can quickly write this together.
Gabber'e hzl bir ekilde yazabiliriz.
Let's add the backdrop css class so that we can use this through css modules and then backdrop should
C \ S S snf arka plann ekleyelim, bylece bu Frue C S S modllerini kullanabilir ve
span the full height and width of the page to cover everything,
sonra her eyi kapsayacak ekilde sayfann tam yksekliini ve geniliini kapsayacak ekilde yedekleyebiliriz.
it should have a fixed position so that it stays in position even as we scroll, it should have a set
Sabit bir konuma sahip olmalyz, bylece kaydrma yaparken bile konumunu korurken
index of let's say 100 so that it is above the elements you want to have it sit up of
ayarlanm bir dizin olmas gerekir, bylece 100 olmasn istediiniz elerin zerinde olacak ekilde ayarlayn.
and this will become important later once we add toolbar, for example
Ve daha sonra, rnein ara ubuu ubuunu eklediimizde bu nemli hale gelecektir.
but if we check out the modal styling, you will see it also has a set index of 500.
Ancak modal stilini kontrol edersek, 500'lk bir dizin dizinine sahip olduunu greceksiniz.
That's of course important,
Bu tabii ki nemlidir.
the modal needs to sit above the backdrop and the backdrop will later need to sit above some other elements
Kalbn arka planda ve zeminin zerinde oturmas ihtiyac daha sonra ara ubuu gibi dier
like the toolbar.
elerin zerinde oturmaldr.
Lets also add
Ekleyelim.
left zero and top zero to position it in the top left corner and let's add a background color where I will
Sol st kedeki sfra sfr brakn ve G harfini kullanacamz bir arka
use a rgba value to set this to a black color with 50% transparency.
plan rengi ekleyin. P. A. deeri yzde 50 effaflkla siyah bir renge ayarlamak iin kullann.
Now it's time to import these classes or this single class actually into the backdrop
imdi ithalat zaman geldi, snfs bu snflar veya benzer snf gerekten zemin
component.
bileenine dntrd.
So here I will therefore simply import classes from ./backdrop css and assign this as
bunu div'ye bir snf ad olarak atayacam, bylece snf ad u anda snfa B snn olduu snflara eit.
a class name to the div, so class name is now equal to classes.Backdrop with a capital B,
Dolaysyla, burada, bu eik izginin C S S esinden classis'i ie aktaracam ve
that's important. With that, we get a backdrop component,
Bu bir zemin bileeni almamz nemlidir.
now we need to use it.
imdi kullanmamz gerekiyor.
It expects to get a show property,
Bir gsteri mal almasn bekliyor.
the question now is where do we add this backdrop
imdi u soru nerede bu zemini ekliyoruz.
and now you can have multiple places where you could add it, where you could argue that it makes sense.
Artk, ekirdek sayfa ieriinin bir paras olmad halde yerleimin dndaki
One such place would be in the app component, have it sit next to the layout, outside of the layout even
yerleime oturmas halinde byle bir yerin derin bileende olmas mantkl olduunu
because it's not part of the core page content.
iddia edebileceiniz yere birden fazla yer ekleyebilirsiniz.
Have it sit in the layout component could you argue because it is part of the page but it should not
Layout bileeninde syledikten, sayfann bir paras olduu iin tartabilirsiniz, ancak ana ieriin bir paras olmamal
be part of the main content and not be part of the toolbar or anything like that.
ve ara ubuunun bir paras veya byle bir ey olmamaldr.
You can definitely do that, you can put it into the layout component,
Kesinlikle bunu dzen bileenine koyabileceinizi yapabilirsin.
you just need to make sure that you then can reach that by passing the show.
Sadece ovu geerek ona ulaabildiinden emin olmanz yeterlidir.
the backdrop state up to that component and so on.
Arka plan l bileene kadar kald ve bu byle devam ediyor.
This is a nice challenge for you,
Bu senin iin gzel bir meydan okumadr.
try placing and handling the backdrop in different places of your app,
Arka plan uygulamanzn farkl yerlerine yerletirip kullanmay deneyin.
for that you might also have to switch some components from stateless functional components to class
bileenlere geirmeniz gerekebilir nk belki birdenbire bir bileende baz yntemleri tanmlamanz gerekir.
based components because maybe all of a sudden, you need to define some method in a component.
Baba iin, baz bileenleri eyaletten daha az ilevsel bileenlerden snf tabanl
I will go for another approach though, I will add the backdrop to my modal because in my opinion, this
Bence modelime zemin katacak olmasna ramen baka bir yaklam benimseyeceim nk bu
backdrop is closely connected to the modal,
zemin modele yakndan bal.
if the modal is shown, the backdrop should be shown. So therefore, I will import my auxiliary components
Modem gsterilirse zemin gsterilmelidir, dolaysyla yardmc bileenlerini buraya alacam nk
here because I need to place that modal next to the backdrop.
modaln arka planna yerletirilmesi gerekiyor.
So let me simply go up all the way to the place where I can access hoc and then my auxiliary
Bu yzden yama Ossi'ye, sonra da yardmcma eriebileceim yere kadar devam etmeme izin verin.
and now let's wrap the div of the modal into this aux component and let's now import the backdrop
Ve imdi def'i modelden bu alks bileenine saralm ve imdi arka plandaki Julias dosyasnn
into this file too, import backdrop from the backdrop folder, the backdrop.js file,
zemin klasrnden zemin ie aktarmak iin bu sonbahara zemin ie aktaralm.
let's place it next to the modal,
Modalin yanna koyalm.
this is my backdrop.
Bu benim arka planm.
Now we should configure the show property on the backdrop because we expect it in there and thankfully,
imdi ov zelliini arka planda yaplandrmalyz nk orada bekliyoruz ve neyse
we get the show information on props in the modal component itself. So we can simply pass on props
ki frn modal bileende bulunan ov hakknda bilgi alyoruz, bylelikle pervanenin ovunu
show to the backdrop,
arka planda geirebiliriz.
if the modal is shown, the backdrop should be shown.
Simgesi gsterilirse zemin gsterilmelidir.
If we do this, let's save all the files and let's see if that works,
Bunu yaparsak tm dosyalar kaydedelim ve ie yarayp yarayp yaramayacan grelim.
looks good,
yi grnyor.
we get a backdrop,
Bir zemin var.
let's make sure that we can click this backdrop too. For that,
Bu arka plan tklayarak babamz seebileceimizden emin olalm.
we of course need to add a click listener inside the backdrop on the div, so onClick
Elbette, tklama zerine lme zemin erevesinde bir tklama dinleyicisi eklemek zorundayz.
should executes some method and of course will receive a reference to that method on a property. So I'll execute
Tabii bir yntem yrtr ve elbette bir mlkte o yntemle ilgili bir referans alacak ve sahne
props
idam edeceim.
and then let's say clicked could be the property name,
Ve sonra diyelim ki toplamak mlk ad olabilir.
you can choose any name you want here
stediiniz herhangi bir ismi seebilirsiniz.
Let's now go back to the modal,
imdi kalba geri dnelim.
here we have to provide a click property and now we have to do something there and I will simply trigger a
Burada bir tklama zellii salamalyz ve imdi burada bir eyler yapmak zorundayz ve Proton'u
prop on that modal which should be modalClosed.
hareket halindeyken kapal olmas gereken Motilal zerinde tetikleyeceim.
So modalClosed is now a property we have to add to the modal component
Dolaysyla, hareketli yakn modal bileene eklemek zorunda olduumuz bir zelliktir.
when we add it to jsx
J.'ye eklediimizde
to our output,
X ktsna.
so to say, and we do of course use that modal in the burger builder
Demek istediim, elbette bu modaliyi burger yapcda kullanyoruz.
here. So what we now need to do is we have to add this modalClosed property to modal because we just
Artk yapmamz gereken ey, bu kalc kapatma zelliklerini modal'a eklemek zorunda olduumuzdan, orada
added it in there as a reference of the method we want to execute
uygulamaya koymak istediimiz yntemi referans olarak eklememizdir.
once the backdrop fires clicked just to reassure that it is clear when this happens, which happens when
Arka plandaki yangnlar tklandnda, tklama tetiklendiinde bu olduunda ne zaman gerekletiinin netletiinden emin
onClick is fired
olmak iin tklandnda.
on the div which makes up the backdrop. So in burger builder where we in the end will get this information,
Arka plan oluturan tm fark, Burgert kurucusunda bu bilgileri sonunda alacamz yer.
I want to execute some code once this backdrop was clicked in the end and I will add a new handler,
Bu zemin sonunda tklandnda baz kodlar altrmak istiyorum ve arka plann tklanmas esasen modaya yaklamak istediimiz ve
the purchaseCancelHandler because clicking the backdrop essentially means that we want to close the modal
satn alma ilemini iptal etmek istediimiz anlamna geldii iin Chase iptal ileyicisine
and that we want to cancel the purchase,
yeni bir ileyici ekleyeceim.
we don't want to continue. So I will call this set state and set purchasing to false, notice the special
istemiyorum, bu set halini arayacam ve kovalamacln, burada kullandm zel indeksin, bu Meffert iindeki ieriin declasse'a deil
syntax I'm using here again to make sure this inside of this method refers to the class and not to something
de baka bir eye iaret etmediinden emin olmak iin tekrar fark etmesini salayacam.
else.
Devam etmek
So it's the purchaseCancelHandler
Yani Paperchase iptalci ileyicisi.
I want to execute once the modal was closed,
Modem kapandktan sonra yrtmek istiyorum.
so this.purchaseCancelHandler.
Bu yzden Chase ncesi iptal ileyicisi.
If we now save everything and we go back to the application and we open the modal, we see it,
Artk her eyi kurtarrsak uygulamaya dnersek modeli aarz onu grrz.
if I click the backdrop, you'll see the modal disappears and the backdrop disappears and we can do this
Arka plan tklarsam modaln kaybolduunu ve zemin kaybolduunu greceiz ve istediimiz
as often as we want.
sklkta bunu yapabiliriz.
This by the way is a super tasty burger,
Bu arada sper lezzetli bir burger var.
no meat but a lot of cheese,
Yumruk deil ama peynir ok.
delicious.
Lezzetli.
Now let's continue and let's make sure we add some buttons as part of the order summary so that we may
imdi devam edelim ve devam etmemiz iin sipari zetinin bir paras olarak baz dmeler eklediimizden
continue
emin olalm.
or that we may cancel.
Veya iptal edebiliriz.